<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.6">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/startbootstrap-clean-blog-jekyll/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/startbootstrap-clean-blog-jekyll/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-04-14T16:31:03+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/startbootstrap-clean-blog-jekyll/feed.xml</id><title type="html">RS Counselling</title><subtitle>A step towards a better you.</subtitle><author><name>Reni Sharma</name></author><entry><title type="html">Anxiety arrising from Covid-19 fears</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/startbootstrap-clean-blog-jekyll/2020/04/14/covid_anxiety.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Anxiety arrising from Covid-19 fears" /><published>2020-04-14T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2020-04-14T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/startbootstrap-clean-blog-jekyll/2020/04/14/covid_anxiety</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/startbootstrap-clean-blog-jekyll/2020/04/14/covid_anxiety.html">&lt;p&gt;Usually, if I wake up sneezing or feel fatigued, I tell myself I am fine, I feel like this because it’s still early in the day and I will feel fine once I have completed my prayers and eaten breakfast. However, recently I have started to notice every little thing which could be a possible symptom of COVID-19 and find myself to start panicking if I think it may be the slightest worry. 
Are you able to relate to this? How can you distinguish your normal behaviors, (which you never really realised before), to whether you have a symptom of COVID without being officially tested?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This may be a frustration amongst many of us which we experience quite often…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This leads me on to discuss my recent experiences where I’ve felt a shortness of breath and breathing difficulties. Now, the first thought I had was that this could be COVID, and I need to see a doctor, IMMEDIATELY. Hastily, I went to my local surgery to see a doctor about this, who advised me to have an X-ray of my chest to see if they could see any infection on my lungs. Fortunately, my X-ray showed that my lungs were clear, but the Doctor informed me that if my breathing difficulties still persist by tomorrow, I should take a trip to the A &amp;amp; E tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although I was happy the scan showed my lungs were functioning fine; with myself being a constant worrier; I started questioning why I was having these breathing difficulties and why the Doctor would refer me to A&amp;amp;E if the symptoms persist. Surely there is something wrong with me, these were the thoughts that kept recurring in my head, (not that I wanted there to be!). I suffered from a terrible night of breathing difficulties and negative thoughts constantly disturbing my mind. My husband was extremely worried and the following morning we found ourselves sitting in the A&amp;amp;E pre-testing ward for symptoms of Coronavirus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whilst we waited patiently, we observed the nurse and support staff and I said a short prayer in my head to thank them a million times for saving people’s lives on a daily basis. 
The doctor ran several tests only to tell me what I had previously heard the day before-that I was in good health, my temperature was optimal, I had no cough, my lungs were clear….&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He then asked me if I have been worrying a lot recently because of this virus and I informed him that I had. He stated that my breathing difficulties may be a form of feeling anxious/worried and reassured me that this is normal to feel like this, and many patients have had similar visits due to feeling anxious about catching COVID.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I breathed with relief and apologised for taking his time up, I automatically felt better knowing I was fine, and felt as though my breathing had returned back to normal. Reflecting on this now, I can relate to how it feels to be anxious about symptoms which may make you believe you have COVID but are due to stress and anxiety.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Undertaking breathing exercises on a daily basis has helped me to feel calm and relaxed as well as taking other precautions by staying home as much as possible, exercising and eating healthily and practising mindfulness. On a final note, for those who have had or have current similar experiences, its okay to feel stressed and anxious about this epidemic, my advice would be to relax, find hobbies or interests, or engage in something you have wanted to do for a long time, to keep your self busy and free from worrying…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more tips on ways to cope, please check out my article on COVID-19 management tips, stay safe and take care.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Reni Sharma</name></author><summary type="html">Usually, if I wake up sneezing or feel fatigued, I tell myself I am fine, I feel like this because it’s still early in the day and I will feel fine once I have completed my prayers and eaten breakfast. However, recently I have started to notice every little thing which could be a possible symptom of COVID-19 and find myself to start panicking if I think it may be the slightest worry. Are you able to relate to this? How can you distinguish your normal behaviors, (which you never really realised before), to whether you have a symptom of COVID without being officially tested? This may be a frustration amongst many of us which we experience quite often… This leads me on to discuss my recent experiences where I’ve felt a shortness of breath and breathing difficulties. Now, the first thought I had was that this could be COVID, and I need to see a doctor, IMMEDIATELY. Hastily, I went to my local surgery to see a doctor about this, who advised me to have an X-ray of my chest to see if they could see any infection on my lungs. Fortunately, my X-ray showed that my lungs were clear, but the Doctor informed me that if my breathing difficulties still persist by tomorrow, I should take a trip to the A &amp;amp; E tomorrow. Although I was happy the scan showed my lungs were functioning fine; with myself being a constant worrier; I started questioning why I was having these breathing difficulties and why the Doctor would refer me to A&amp;amp;E if the symptoms persist. Surely there is something wrong with me, these were the thoughts that kept recurring in my head, (not that I wanted there to be!). I suffered from a terrible night of breathing difficulties and negative thoughts constantly disturbing my mind. My husband was extremely worried and the following morning we found ourselves sitting in the A&amp;amp;E pre-testing ward for symptoms of Coronavirus. Whilst we waited patiently, we observed the nurse and support staff and I said a short prayer in my head to thank them a million times for saving people’s lives on a daily basis. The doctor ran several tests only to tell me what I had previously heard the day before-that I was in good health, my temperature was optimal, I had no cough, my lungs were clear…. He then asked me if I have been worrying a lot recently because of this virus and I informed him that I had. He stated that my breathing difficulties may be a form of feeling anxious/worried and reassured me that this is normal to feel like this, and many patients have had similar visits due to feeling anxious about catching COVID. I breathed with relief and apologised for taking his time up, I automatically felt better knowing I was fine, and felt as though my breathing had returned back to normal. Reflecting on this now, I can relate to how it feels to be anxious about symptoms which may make you believe you have COVID but are due to stress and anxiety. Undertaking breathing exercises on a daily basis has helped me to feel calm and relaxed as well as taking other precautions by staying home as much as possible, exercising and eating healthily and practising mindfulness. On a final note, for those who have had or have current similar experiences, its okay to feel stressed and anxious about this epidemic, my advice would be to relax, find hobbies or interests, or engage in something you have wanted to do for a long time, to keep your self busy and free from worrying… For more tips on ways to cope, please check out my article on COVID-19 management tips, stay safe and take care.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Stay at home blues? 7 ways to cope</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/startbootstrap-clean-blog-jekyll/2020/04/14/covid_coping.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Stay at home blues? 7 ways to cope" /><published>2020-04-14T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2020-04-14T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/startbootstrap-clean-blog-jekyll/2020/04/14/covid_coping</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/startbootstrap-clean-blog-jekyll/2020/04/14/covid_coping.html">&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h1 id=&quot;have-a-spring-clean&quot;&gt;Have a Spring Clean&lt;/h1&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Cleaning your house by getting rid of the things you do not need or haven’t used in a while can be a therapeutic way of keeping active and busy. It may also help you to reorganise your mind and declutter any negative thoughts you may be having.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h1 id=&quot;exercise&quot;&gt;Exercise&lt;/h1&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Keeping your body moving and active is a great way of keeping healthy and focused. It can also motivate your mood, help you to keep positive and energised as well as being a stress relief from everything else that is on your mind. 
If you find it difficult to exercise alone, you could always make use of an online workout video, or pair up with one of your friends and do a workout together through Whatsapp video call or Facetime.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h1 id=&quot;meditate&quot;&gt;Meditate&lt;/h1&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Release any stress or tension you may be experiencing by practising regular meditation. This technique has proven to be successful in calming your mind, keeping you focused and feeling positive and energised to carry on with your day.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h1 id=&quot;cook-and-eat-healthy-meals&quot;&gt;Cook and eat healthy meals&lt;/h1&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Whilst the majority of people are stocking up on tinned and canned foods, which may be convenient for the long-term, now is a good time to consider buying fresh produce and cooking your own healthy meals. I am sure you are aware that as much as takeaways may taste great, they are not healthy with the unknown amounts of sugar and ingredients added to them. Why not try cooking your own food as you will know exactly what is going into it and it can be a chance to ensure you are getting your 5 fruits and day vegetables into your diet too.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h1 id=&quot;learn-a-new-skill&quot;&gt;Learn a new skill&lt;/h1&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Use this extra time you have to learn something new. Whether it’s taking an online course in learning how to cook, completing a online workshop on building your C.V or learning skills which enhance the way you work and what you currently do. When you do go back into work, you will be better equipped with more knowledge and skills then you were before.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h1 id=&quot;write-letterssend-emails-to-your-friends-and-family&quot;&gt;Write letters/send emails to your friends and family&lt;/h1&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Although you may be missing your loved ones at this time, in this day and age there are plenty of ways that you are able to keep in touch with them, some of these are through Watssapp, Facetime, Skype, Twitter…. However, if you want to make it more personal, why not try writing a letter or sending an email saying how you feel and discussing your thoughts with them.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h1 id=&quot;write-a-reflection-diary&quot;&gt;Write a reflection diary&lt;/h1&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Every other day of the year you may have been running around, completing errands, going into work, going to college, shopping, eating out, meeting up with friends. However, now that you’ve been asked to work from home, quarantined or simply staying at home because you are worried about catching the virus, consider this as the best time to step back and reflect on the past months where you may not have had a chance to.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Writing a reflection diary can be a useful way of keeping a track of what you have done so far, what you are currently doing and what you would like to achieve in the future. It may simply be a diary involving your daily thoughts or anxieties, research has shown that writing down what’s on your mind can be an effective way of coping with stressors and worries.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Reni Sharma</name></author><summary type="html">Have a Spring Clean Cleaning your house by getting rid of the things you do not need or haven’t used in a while can be a therapeutic way of keeping active and busy. It may also help you to reorganise your mind and declutter any negative thoughts you may be having.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Lighting a lamp to mark the fight against Coronavirus</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/startbootstrap-clean-blog-jekyll/2020/04/14/lamp.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Lighting a lamp to mark the fight against Coronavirus" /><published>2020-04-14T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2020-04-14T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/startbootstrap-clean-blog-jekyll/2020/04/14/lamp</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/startbootstrap-clean-blog-jekyll/2020/04/14/lamp.html">&lt;p&gt;This initiative was derived from India’s Prime Minister, Narenda Modi who tweeted, “Salute to the light of the lamp which brings auspiciousness, health and prosperity, which destroys negative feelings,” which consequently led to millions of residents responding to his appeal by lighting a ‘Diya’, candle or simply by switching on their phones torch light.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The significance of lighting a candle in Hindu culture demonstrates great intellectual and spiritual significance. It can portray hope, enlightenment and be a way of showing strong community for individuals. During this epidemic period, I believe it is extremely important that we come together to tackle Coronavirus, and if this simply involves everyone taking out around 10 minutes of their day to light a candle, then this collective symbolism can give us the confidence, power and strength to fight this Coronavirus battle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Likewise, me and my husband who are residing in Singapore at the moment; showed our commitment to Modi’s appeal by lighting a candle at 11.30pm (which constitutes 9pm in India’s local time). This experience was inspirational and brought back memories for us both of us during our childhood times where our families would light a diya on a daily basis to create positivity within the household.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;India has been in a strict lockdown from March 25 which will last 21 days in total. Cases have emerged 3,577 in total with over 85 deaths as the virus continues to spread. In my opinion, what the country needs (as well as the whole world) is this kind of drive and determination to collaborate together in unity and overcome this struggle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leaving you all with a final message which was delivered from the Prime Minister who shared: 
“Let the brightness of the lights ignite our energies and ensure the ‘victory of good over evil. My prayers go out for all those million homes across the planet who are suffering because of coronavirus. I call upon them all to be a part of this symbolic war over evil forces.” These words have touched my heart and hope that it will ignite the minds of many others in this time of desperation. Stay safe!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Reni Sharma</name></author><summary type="html">This initiative was derived from India’s Prime Minister, Narenda Modi who tweeted, “Salute to the light of the lamp which brings auspiciousness, health and prosperity, which destroys negative feelings,” which consequently led to millions of residents responding to his appeal by lighting a ‘Diya’, candle or simply by switching on their phones torch light.</summary></entry></feed>